hello now heroes
你好现在英雄
we're just about to start our pack talk
我们将要开始我们的打包谈话
our first ever Jakarta Tech Talk now let
我们的第一次雅加达技术讲座现在让
me first introduce myself so my name is
我先自我介绍，所以我的名字是
Daniel Brad rich and I got this fabulous
丹尼尔·布拉德（Daniel Brad）富有，我对此赞不绝口
opportunity to be your Jakarta a program
有机会成为您的雅加达程序
manager so today we're starting with our
经理，所以今天我们开始
new series and we're hoping to discuss
新系列，我们希望讨论
topics related to not just Jakarta Eve
与雅加达除夕有关的主题
but Java cloud native topics as well and
但是Java云原生主题也是如此
we are starting with the first tactic
我们从第一个战术开始
from Italia who is right here as well so
来自意大利的人也是如此
Italia will be talking about the Jakarta
意大利将谈论雅加达
needs no SQL the the specification that
不需要SQL的规范
is going to be under Jakarta EE and then
将在Jakarta EE下进行，然后
we'll listen when Eaton is going to talk
当伊顿说话时我们会听
a little bit about the process and what
关于过程的一点点
we can do to start things off and then
我们可以开始做一些事情，然后
we'll open the session for questions and
我们将在会议上提出问题并
answers so with this little intro I
答案就这么简单
don't want to waste too much time and I
不想浪费太多时间，我
will just hand it over to Italia and
将其交给意大利
have you can I take it from here and
你能从这里拿走吗
tell us all about Jakarta NoSQL okay
告诉我们所有有关Jakarta NoSQL的信息
thank you
谢谢
I mean glad to be here twice the first
我是很高兴第一次来这里两次
one because they're gonna be the first
一个，因为他们将成为第一个
guy to do the Jakarta series and I'm
做雅加达系列的人，我是
going to leave the first specification
即将离开第一个规范
in Jakarta he right so I'm going to talk
在雅加达，他说得对，所以我要谈谈
about your tartar beef snow Seco because
关于你的牙垢牛肉雪山高，因为
no seeker gonna be the first
没有寻求者会成为第一个
specifications in the Jakarta world so
雅加达世界中的规格
my name is Otto Santana
我叫奥托·桑塔纳
let's share my screen one second
一秒钟分享一下我的屏幕
so Tanya can you see my screen those
所以Tanya可以看到我的萤幕吗
everybody can see my screen let's see
每个人都可以看到我的屏幕
okay you can see my scooty right now so
好吧，你现在可以看到我的傻瓜，所以
I don't talk about about it my twitter
我不谈论我的推特
handle is otaku Java so I'm a Twitter
句柄是宅男Java，所以我是Twitter
fan please follow me and I came to do
粉丝请跟我来，我来做
some news about the new specification
有关新规范的一些消息
about the gay no secret products so let
关于同性恋没有秘密产品，所以让
me reduce you the whole idea here is
我减少你的整个想法是
talk about Jakarta no secret
谈论雅加达没有秘密
specification but first I need to talk
规范，但首先我需要谈谈
about what no sicko is so no secret is a
关于没有病是什么，所以没有秘密是
different kind of assistance technology
不同种类的辅助技术
yes there's a database so input
是的，有一个数据库，所以输入
information there we can try information
信息在那里我们可以尝试信息
for their update and delete information
有关其更新和删除信息
but they don't use the structure they
但他们不使用他们的结构
usually don't have transaction and we
通常没有交易，我们
have here five different types of no
这里有五种不同类型的否
sequel database the first one is key
续集数据库第一个是关键
value so we have a several
值，所以我们有几个
implementation of this kind it looks
这种实现看起来
like a key hash map or map
像是散列图或地图
implementation from the job world so
来自职场的实施
given key I can retrieve some
给定密钥，我可以检索一些
information from this key for example I
例如，来自此密钥的信息
have the Apollo that returns the Sun
拥有返回太阳的阿波罗
areas the world so keep the key I can
围绕世界，所以我要保持钥匙
return the value the next one is a
返回值下一个是
column family so here we have the
列族，所以我们在这里
structure
结构体
let's look like key very however it has
让我们看起来很像钥匙，但是它有
it stars the very on different way each
各自以不同的方式突出
information going to be storage in the
信息将存储在
column as you can see here for example
例如，您可以在此处看到的列
after did it has a column that had the
之后是否有一个具有
information loving and happy and
信息充满爱与快乐
color that has the pink information so
具有粉红色信息的颜色
we have again we have a several
我们又有几个
implementation I believe the most
我最相信的实施
popular one is Apache Cassandra but you
最受欢迎的是Apache Cassandra，但您
have a busy skill Adibi as well going to
有一个忙碌的技能阿迪比以及
the third no secret on a base type we
第三个基本类型的秘密
have the document the structure looks
具有结构的文件
like XML or JSON five we have a several
像XML或JSON，我们有五个
implementation and the mum-to-be
实施和未来妈妈
is so far the most popular no sequel
是迄今为止最受欢迎的续集
database famous around the world so if
数据库闻名世界，如果
you hear about mobile to be yes that's a
您听说手机是肯定的
no simple database of the type document
没有类型文档的简单数据库
and we have also the graph the graph
我们还有图
keep the relationship between the fact X
保持事实X之间的关系
you can see here we have Apollo Aires
您可以在这里看到我们有Apollo Aires
and Kratos and we keep the relationship
和Kratos，我们保持关系
between the sky here okay what the
在这里的天空之间好吗
difference between this technology and
这项技术与
SQL technology it's because I put the
SQL技术是因为我把
direction here for example I can say
例如这里的方向我可以说
Kratos cute Apollo and I can say again
Kratos可爱的阿波罗，我可以再说一遍
Apollo was cute by Kratos so I have
阿波罗很可爱，所以我有
direction to my relationship here and
我的恋爱方向
the last one is a mood model basically a
最后一个是情绪模型
mood model is when one no psycho
情绪模型是没有心理的时候
implementer implements water one type
实施者实施一种水
for example I have already be that
例如我已经是
implements two different types graph and
实现两种不同类型的图和
document so that's a good model okay
文档，这是一个很好的模型
usually when you talk about no seeker
通常当你谈论没有寻求者
you think about SQL technology so here
您考虑使用SQL技术，因此在这里
the difference
区别
we don't have have enough time to to
我们没有足够的时间去
talk about the chief
谈论酋长
different but black show here is the
不同，但这里的黑色表演是
structure matter and it's no single type
结构很重要，而且不是单一类型
has a different structure in a different
在不同的地方有不同的结构
reality
现实
for example SQL has relationship and
例如，SQL具有关系和
Kaveri and the column don't have
Kaveri和专栏没有
relationship and rest
关系和休息
I have entire object to hold the
我有整个物件要拿
relationship and also the direction of
关系以及方向
the properties so I can go deep or
属性，以便我可以深入了解
relationship with graph deeper then SQL
与图的关系比SQL更深
relational technology and ok let's talk
关系技术，好吧，我们来谈谈
about the application the job
关于申请工作
application you use in both base TCO
您在两个基本TCO中使用的应用程序
technology on this hand here I have the
这边的技术我在
relation relation application that I
我的关系申请
have the my logic application and then I
有我的逻辑应用程序，然后我
have my dau data access object if I'm
如果我有我的dau数据访问对象
using the standards I have the JPA in
使用我拥有JPA的标准
the JDBC so JPA is the mapping layer so
JDBC，因此JPA是映射层，因此
I have my objects and put some
我有我的东西，放一些
annotation and the JDBC the stay now
注释和JDBC至今
communication so basically it's going to
沟通，所以基本上
use SQL gonna communicate directly to
使用SQL将直接与
the database in the other hand I have
另一方面，数据库
the no see complication so the different
没有看到并发症，所以不同
here is because I don't have other
这是因为我没有其他
studies yet so I have one API two
研究还没有，所以我有一个API两个
different kind of no signal base that
另一种没有信号的基础
means if I'd like to change and if you
意味着如果我想改变，如果你
learn a new API I need to change my
学习新的API我需要更改我的
whole API application and the first
整个API应用程序和第一个
solution that people are looking for is
人们正在寻找的解决方案是
why I don't use jp8 use of nocebo issues
为什么我不使用jp8使用nocebo问题
the first reason is because
第一个原因是因为
JPA was created to SQL technology so the
JPA是根据SQL技术创建的，因此
API did not cover something like saves a
API未涵盖诸如保存
secretly the time to leave definition
偷偷离开定义的时间
the constants level in one portent thing
一件重要事情中的常数水平
here or no super database is because the
这里或没有超级数据库是因为
diversity matter to know seeker word so
所以知道求职者单词的多样性很重要
we have Cassandra that has specific
我们有具体的卡桑德拉
behavior that a lot use and you look you
经常使用的行为，看起来
have the solution we have created the
有我们创建的解决方案
Eclipse general safe solution that
Eclipse通用安全解决方案
looked like the JPA JDBC solution and
看起来像JPA JDBC解决方案，
they have a small difference because we
它们之间的差异很小，因为我们
have the mapping you have the
有你的映射
communication and we have to H no Seco
沟通，我们必须H没有山高
type on different API so one API to call
在不同的API上键入，因此可以调用一个API
out one if you actually dock me and want
如果你真的停靠我想要
to try to key in one API to graph
尝试键入一个API进行图形绘制
database okay so do I have two different
数据库好了，所以我有两个不同
it guys we have API to communication you
伙计们，我们有API与您交流
want to create a mapping as you can see
想创建一个映射，如您所见
here we are looking for the
在这里我们正在寻找
communication native API we have the
通讯本机API
around DB we have MongoDB who have count
在数据库周围，我们有MongoDB，他们有
pace and arraign DB all these got here
步调和提神DB都到了
are no single database and also our
不是单一的数据库，也是我们的
tockman no signal base and as you can
托克曼没有信号基地，你可以
see here the class are different the
看到这里的班级不同
method name are it's different but they
方法名称不同，但是它们
try to do the exactly same thing if the
如果尝试执行完全相同的操作
document tried to put the information
文件试图放信息
there name a value why not just use one
有一个值为什么不只使用一个
and
和
face each provider implements of this
面对每个提供商的实现
way this war what are you looking for
这样的战争你在找什么
and again the diversity matters so we
多样性又很重要，所以我们
can see here some some interface that
可以在这里看到一些界面
has much glow implementation and also we
有很多焕发的实现，而且我们
have some features belongs just to
有一些功能只是属于
Cassandra the cql because the QL means
Cassandra的cql，因为QL表示
custom require language and the last
自定义要求语言和最后
line he is a coefficient level that just
他是一个系数水平
belongs to Cassandra and okay you talked
属于卡桑德拉，好吧，你说了
about the communication layer so let's
关于通信层，所以让我们
talk about the memory the map it looks
谈谈它看起来的内存图
like the Jaypee so have some annotation
像Jaypee，所以有一些注释
such as HT column ID so free content and
例如HT列ID，因此免费内容和
we have some specific a specific
我们有一些具体的
communication to this mapping layer so
与该映射层的通信，因此
for example here we have the document in
例如在这里我们有文件
place that is to connect you document
连接文档的地方
type and one type intensive field is
类型和一种类型的密集字段是
that we have the hippo store concept so
我们有河马店的概念
basically we have the interface we
基本上我们有接口
creating the face we extend the hip on
创造我们延伸臀部的脸
star interface and done the frame you're
星形界面并完成了框架
gonna implement everything to you
会为您实现一切
present to here I buy Commission so I
现在到这里我买佣金，所以我
created method fine by name and that
创建的方法按名称正确
high posts are from God so it's gonna
高职位是从上帝那里来的
find by name if it returned just one God
通过名称查找它是否只返回了一位上帝
with optional also one can use find by
与可选的也可以使用查找由
name and age or by something so we use
名称和年龄或其他，所以我们使用
the convention we can do some queries
约定我们可以做一些查询
and again at the communication layer the
在通讯层上
mapping matter letters the diversity
映射问题说明了多样性
matters so we have something like
很重要，所以我们有类似
UDT annotation that user file type that
UDT注释表示该用户文件类型
belongs just to Cassandra no secret
只是属于卡桑德拉而已
enemies a stay cql annotation that's run
与运行的Stay CQL注释成为敌人
secure and then convert you god entity
安全，然后将您转换为上帝实体
and one cool feature is we have the
一个很酷的功能是
queries by x so as you can see here i
x的查询，这样您就可以在这里看到
have the top multi-plate that the
有顶部的多板
operation to document have the
操作要有文件
contemplate that the column and that the
考虑该列和
skull operation t value in graph as you
您在图形中的颅骨手术t值
can see here the query are different
可以在这里看到查询是不同的
because the structure are different so
因为结构不同所以
and then we have the first statement we
然后我们有第一个陈述
have something like we usually do on OS
像我们通常在OS上一样
care technology use on no safe word okay
护理技术的使用没有安全感
and of course giving the posture i can
当然给我姿势
use some query annotation and use some
使用一些查询注释并使用一些
some parameters and they couldn't permit
一些参数，他们不允许
automatically choo-choo-choo to us oh I
自动选择我们，哦，我
will even have time to show addy move
甚至有时间展示爸爸的举动
any let's share a different screen
任何让我们共享不同的屏幕
that's not here okay he is my simple I I
不好，他是我简单的二
have an entity that's a god empty so
有一个神是空的实体，所以
that has someone rotation as you see
看到有人在旋转
here so I have the God I have some ID
在这里，我有上帝，我有一些身份证
annotation to say okay this integral the
注释说好吧，这个积分
street here is ID I have the column and
这条街是我有列的ID，
that's a Java object right so I have my
那是一个Java对象，所以我有
pewter he is not pewter so
锡，他不是锡，所以
and I have a simplest way to start my no
我有一个最简单的方法开始
single database is using docker compose
单个数据库正在使用docker compose
as you can see here I have Reddy's
如您所见，这里有Reddy
Cassandra Mongo Mongo DB neo4j and and
Cassandra Mongo Mongo DB neo4j和
have JSON file that has our
有包含我们的JSON文件
configuration that jano sync needs so as
jano sync需要的配置，例如
you see here it's a JSON file so the
您会看到这里是JSON文件，因此
first one here belongs to key value and
这里的第一个属于键值，
Stephanie who one belongs you the column
属于您的斯蒂芬妮专栏
that are you using Cassandra the third
你在用卡桑德拉第三
one is to document
一种是记录
there you are using code base and the
在那里您正在使用代码库，
last one is the graph database they are
最后一个是图形数据库
using neo4j we have the Godhead Porter
使用neo4j我们有Godhead Porter
as you can see here there's no
如您所见，这里没有
implementation do this guy the whole
实施整个这家伙
idea here is to the general Seco
这里的想法是山高将军
implement it's automatically to me to me
对我来说自动实现
okay I have the off sample here is gonna
好吧，我这里有样品
be in the github so you can study you
在github上，所以你可以研究你
can go to get more information about it
可以获取有关它的更多信息
I'm gonna pick one to run some demo as
我要选一个来运行一些演示
you can you see here it's a CD IQ goes
你可以看到这是CD IQ
oh so our static container using the
哦，所以我们的静态容器使用
java SE and then I checked my posture I
Java SE，然后检查姿势
create my my entity in the new safe and
在新的保险箱中创建我的实体，
it ends it I can't find my ID as I
它结束了，因为我找不到我的ID
totally I think creates my hunk ovation
完全是我的想法
here so find my name I can find object
在这里找到我的名字我可以找到对象
by the name there's something he
名叫他有事
happened with this sample here this time
这次在这里发生了这个样品
with the document so the whole idea is I
与文件，所以整个想法是我
start the container
启动容器
have my template and this template here
有我的模板和这个模板在这里
you can do some operation can make some
你可以做一些操作可以做一些
operation to us only easy way of course
操作对我们来说是唯一简单的方法
we have a query as you can see here what
我们有一个查询，您可以在这里看到
I'm doing is static imports and you are
我正在做的是静态导入，而您正在
using he fruity guys so select key all
用他果味的家伙，所以选择所有关键
the fields from God were renamed easy
上帝的田地更名为易
code dianna and then I have my query to
代码戴安娜，然后我将查询
document operation and there came we
文档操作，我们来了
tribe this guy here okay I can also
部落这个家伙在这里好吧我也可以
define the TTL so remember the whole
定义TTL，所以要记住整个
idea he is to define the time to the
他的想法是要定义时间
date tea leaves of the database so as
日期数据库的茶叶，以便
you see here the duration is from one
您会看到持续时间从一个开始
second so if you go exit for two seconds
秒，所以如果你走了两秒钟
when I'm done again it's gonna return
当我再次做完它会回来
empty the key value of course is one is
空键值当然是一个
move girls key value basically I came
移动女孩的关键价值基本上我来了
with charges for the key so I create my
与钥匙的费用，所以我创建我的
HT Diana I returned it from the key
HT Diana我从钥匙归还了它
Diana I can't find the time to leave
戴安娜，我找不到时间离开
again use my key
再次使用我的钥匙
mikey is totally monitoring here
mikey完全在这里监视
remember key value is look like the map
记住关键值看起来像地图
from java and the last one that's a
来自java，最后一个是
light show more is my graph database
显示更多是我的图形数据库
I believe the graph database is more
我相信图形数据库更多
different one if you look for SQL
如果您要查找SQL，则不同
technology so I have my graph template
技术，所以我有我的图形模板
again to operation to graph and then I
再次进行图形操作，然后我
create two two empties
创建两个两个空
Diana in Apollo I'm certain in the
我肯定在阿波罗的戴安娜
database I use some trans actor to say
我用一些反式演员说
okay it's time to go to the database and
好了，该到数据库了
then I do a query as you can see this
然后我进行查询，您可以看到
one is something different from document
一个不同于文件
so give my vertex that has got label it
所以给我的顶点加上标签
has the name Diana and Don it's return
名字叫戴安娜和唐
Diana in the in column and then a
Diana in in栏，然后
creative relationship between sky here
天空之间的创意关系
so if Diana I can say Diana is brother
所以如果戴安娜我可以说戴安娜是兄弟
of Apollo and Apollo is also brother
和阿波罗也是兄弟
from Diana why this wipe this buff
来自戴安娜（Diana）为何要擦拭此抛光
relationship because again graph has
关系，因为图再次具有
erections and I can do more queries as
勃起，我可以做更多的查询
you can see here if my rhetoric that has
你可以在这里看到我的言论是否
got a slave up that has a Diane name and
有一个戴安娜名字的奴隶
then you can return from family so if a
那么你可以从家人那里回来，如果
god that has a broader relationship in
拥有更广泛关系的神
the blood she returned both so that's
她返回的血都是
the result so let's start the talker
结果，让我们开始说话
here on second with this graph database
这是第二个与此图形数据库
and okay it's sad it's a docker so let's
好吧，很遗憾，这是一个码头工人，让我们
run sky here
在这里奔跑
let's run I'm gonna stop show this we
让我们运行，我要停止显示这个，我们
squeak here and then I'm gonna show the
吱吱声在这里，然后我要展示
neo4j console this little guy here as
neo4j控制台这个小家伙在这里
you can see I can do some operation but
你可以看到我可以做一些手术，但是
for now as you can see I have Diana that
现在您可以看到我有戴安娜
is brother for Apollo in Apollo that's
是阿波罗的阿波罗的兄弟
brother phone Diana usually
哥哥电话戴安娜通常
recommendation engine use graph database
推荐引擎使用图数据库
a lot mostly there for gate and as you
很多东西都在那里
can see my hope code I'm using a
可以看到我正在使用的希望代码
shipment code again I use a comma API so
再次使用货件代码，所以我使用逗号API
I have my communication here laying here
我在这里交流
that is ready tsuki value Cassandra to
准备好tsuki值卡桑德拉到
column the count base document and I
列计数基础文件和我
came chin that so okay
下巴就这么好
I'm let you use column but eight days I
我让你用专栏，但是我八天
just need to change that that dependents
只需要改变那个依赖
to eight page driver oh I'd like to use
到八页驱动程序哦，我想用
hazel cast it steady ready so I just
淡褐色稳定地准备好了，所以我只是
replace these deputies here - okay this
在这里替换这些代表-好的
time I'm going to use heads of cast
时间我要使用演员头像
instead of readies
代替准备
hey let's return to slides slides and
嘿，让我们回到幻灯片
then we did you did that presentation
那我们做了你的演讲
right now have some providers some
现在有一些供应商
noshiko providers that eclipse you know
noshiko提供者，让您黯然失色
Seco offer if you watch you so help
山高报价，如果你看着你这么帮助
support Cassandra is he a large third
支持卡桑德拉是他的三分之一
Haram DB or NDB and one part if he here
Haram DB或NDB，如果他在这里，则分为一部分
is the Carter no Seco when I use a
当我使用
kitchen oseco reference interpretation
厨房oseco参考解释
that is my presentation Wayne this
那是我的演讲韦恩
that's all is there in fashion but I
那就是时尚的全部，但我
believe waiting that'll be first I'm
相信等着我
ready to take over but Stephanie and and
准备接手，但斯蒂芬妮和
Tonya do we need to any or any business
Tonya我们需要任何或任何业务
before I do that you were what was the
在我这样做之前，你是什么
question
题
Wayne I'm sorry I'm part of it partner
韦恩（Wayne），我很抱歉成为我的合作伙伴
me as I'm just ready to take over I was
我正准备接管我
all right okay here we go
好的，好的，我们开始
I am screen-sharing so can I safely
我正在共享屏幕，所以我可以安全地
assume Octavio can you a nod your head
假设Octavio可以点头吗
that you see a a slide that says Eclipse
您会看到一张显示Eclipse的幻灯片
Foundation specification process yeah
基础规范流程
okay excellent okay good so I only have
好的，好的，好的，所以我只有
a couple of minutes I had planned to to
我原本打算去
speak only for
只为
and and I might come a little shorter
而且我可能会矮一点
than that I just want to talk a little
比我只想谈一点
bit about where we are in the process
关于我们在过程中的位置
and sort of make sure that we as a
并确保我们作为一个
community are on on the same page or
社区在同一页面上，或
thinking the same sort of thing about
想着同样的事情
about what what's next so just to
关于接下来会发生什么
refresh everybody's memory x' our goals
刷新每个人的记忆x我们的目标
with this effort are first to push out a
通过这种努力，首先要推出一个
clip GlassFish of 5.1 now eclipse
剪辑5.1的GlassFish现在黯然失色
GlassFish 5.1 is implementing the
GlassFish 5.1正在实施
existing Java EE 8 specifications and
现有的Java EE 8规范和
that's due out next week it looks like
下周就要到期了
we're we're on track for a release of
我们正在按计划发布
that and that's frankly represents a
那并坦率地表示一个
huge amount of work from all sorts of
各种各样的工作
people and and that's a wonderful thing
人，那是一件了不起的事情
in my mind certainly though there has
在我心中当然有
been we've allowed a few invalid but I
我们已经允许了一些无效，但我
tend to prefer is invalid intermediate
倾向于首选无效的中间体
states through this implementation so
通过此实现说明
the part of what we need to do following
接下来我们需要做的部分
this is to clean up a couple of things
这是为了清理几件事
but but by and large this has been a
但总的来说，这已经是一个
great effort and looking forward to you
努力，期待你
know rolling up our sleeves and
知道卷起袖子，
continuing the the next the next stage
继续下一个下一阶段
actually the next stage is actually
实际上下一阶段是
pushing out something the Jakarta ee8
推出一些雅加达EE8
specifications themselves so you know
自己说明，所以你知道
like I said the the the work that we've
就像我说的，我们所做的工作
been doing we've done so far on
到目前为止，我们一直在做
GlassFish has been about moving the
GlassFish一直在移动
existing content over to the Eclipse
现有内容移至Eclipse
Foundation to get us into a position
建立我们基础的基础
where we can move forward
我们可以前进的地方
so with Jakarta ee8 now it's a matter of
因此，现在使用Jakarta ee8可以解决
actually implementing our specification
实际执行我们的规范
process taking the existing
现有过程
specification content that we have and
我们拥有的规范内容
actually turning them into real Jakarta
实际上把他们变成真正的雅加达
branded specifications and that's going
品牌规格，这就是
to be an interesting bit of work as well
也是一件有趣的工作
once we get to that point and we declare
一旦到达这一点，我们就宣布
success on the Jakarta ee8 then we're
在Jakarta ee8上取得成功，那么我们
looking at the really exciting part of
看着真正令人兴奋的部分
the
的
which is the the the opening up the
这是开放的
floodgates and allowing real interesting
闸门，并允许真正有趣
new new development work to go on one of
新的新开发工作将继续进行
the things we're trying to do and and I
我们正在尝试做的事情，而我
hope that the community appreciates this
希望社区对此表示赞赏
is we're trying to keep Jakarta ee8 will
是我们要保持雅加达ee8会
be the offer functional parity with Java
与Java提供功能相等
EE 8 we're trying to minimize the amount
EE 8我们正在努力减少数量
of of change that occurs in the code
代码中发生的变化
bases and in the specification documents
基础和规格文件中
themselves this should result in they
自己这应该导致他们
know what we're looking for probably be
知道我们在寻找什么
minor modifications of source files the
源文件的微小修改
comments that sort of thing no changes
评论那种事情没有改变
in method signatures changes of
方法签名的变化
specification names possibly that sort
规范名称可能是那种
of thing
的东西
wanted to talk a little bit about what
想谈点什么
specification projects themselves will
规范项目本身将
look like the a little bit different
看起来有点不同
than what we used to do with the JCP as
比起我们过去使用JCP做的
I look through the various J SRS I seen
我看了看过的各种J SRS
you know multiple jsr is that different
你知道多个jsr是不同的
compositions of teams and whatnot for
团队的组成及其他
the various specifications as they
他们的各种规格
evolve with the Eclipse Foundation
与Eclipse Foundation一起发展
specification process we have one
规范过程，我们有一个
persistent project that is responsible
负责任的持久项目
for creating one or more specifications
用于创建一个或多个规范
the project has a team of committers and
该项目有一个提交者团队，
and like any other open source project
和其他任何开源项目一样
at the Eclipse Foundation committers are
Eclipse Foundation的提交者是
added to the roles removed from the
添加到从中删除的角色
roles there's a natural way that that
角色有一种自然的方式
themes change over time but the fact is
主题随时间而改变，但事实是
that there will be a single team that
会有一个团队
that moves forward multiple versions of
向前移动多个版本
any particular specification now I did
我现在做了任何特定的规格
say that a specification project may
说规范项目可能
handle multiple specifications we
处理多种规格我们
actually have a project it's called
实际有一个项目叫做
Eclipse project for
的Eclipse专案
Abell Jakarta EEE api's and this this
Abell Jakarta EEE API和这个
project actually holds five
该项目实际上拥有五个
specifications right now or is intended
现在或预期的规格
to hold five specifications the idea
持有五个规格的想法
being that as specifications become more
随着规格的增加
stable and there are a lot of potential
稳定，潜力很大
for innovation and we decide that it's
为了创新，我们决定
not about something that's going to to
而不是要去做的事情
grow significantly we can aggregate
显着增长，我们可以聚合
projects into our education specific
专为我们的教育项目
ations into into this project or or into
进入这个项目或
others so you know very much a
其他人，所以你非常了解
maintenance style project and there's a
维护风格的项目，还有一个
couple of other cases where a single
其他一些情况下，
specification project may hold multiple
规范项目可能包含多个
specifications I thought I'd talk a
我以为我会说一个规范
little bit about when we use the word
关于什么时候我们使用这个词
specification specification is one of
规范规范是其中之一
those words that we tend to overload the
我们倾向于超载的那些词
we refer to in the specification process
我们在规范过程中提到
a specification document again very
规格文件又很
often people will use when they may when
人们通常会在可能的时候使用
they say the word specification they
他们说的是规范字
mean the specification document we think
是指我们认为的规格文件
of the specification being the entirety
规范的全部
of the artifacts that make up a
构成
particular specification and in fact I'm
特定的规格，实际上我是
actually calling a calling out day a
实际将召集日称为
specific version of a specification with
规范的特定版本
this diagram this particular particular
这个图这个特殊的
version of a specification will have a
规范的版本将有一个
document it will have certain technical
文件将具有一定的技术性
artifacts in the javis basis manifests
贾维斯基础上的文物表现出来
as API files interfaces that sort of
作为API文件的接口
thing a specification version also has a
规范版本也有一个东西
TCK and pointers to one or more
TCK和指向一个或多个的指针
compatible implementations now this is
兼容的实现，现在是
another place where we we differ from
我们不同于的另一个地方
the JCP we don't have a notion of a
在JCP，我们没有
single reference implementation instead
单一参考实现
we have a notion of compatible
我们有一个兼容的概念
implementations and one of the
实现和之一
requirements for a specification is that
规格要求是
there must be at least one compatible
必须至少有一个兼容
implementation using an open-source
使用开源实现
license the list of open-source
许可开源列表
licenses is currently and I'm going to
许可证当前，我要
flip over to make sure I get this right
翻转以确保我做对了
the eclipse public license the Eclipse
Eclipse Eclipse的公共许可证
distribution license which is a bsd
bsd的发行许可证
three clause or the Apache License
三个条款或Apache许可
version 2 so again for to be a
版本2因此再次成为
specification according to our process
根据我们的工艺规格
there must be a compatible
必须有一个兼容的
implementation under one of those
其中之一的实施
open-source licenses now that's not to
开源许可证现在不是
say there can't be implementations under
说不能有实现
other licenses and certainly an
其他许可证，当然还有
implementation that conforms to the
符合
specification would be said to be
规格可以说是
compatible independent of its license
独立于其许可而兼容
the the notion here though is that in
这里的概念是
order for a specification to be valid
规格有效的命令
there must be at least one compatible
必须至少有一个兼容
implementation under one of those
其中之一的实施
licenses I'm hoping that's not that not
许可证，我希望不是那样
made things more confusing so we combine
使事情变得更加混乱，因此我们将
these various artifacts into like I said
这些各种各样的文物变成我所说的
a particular version of a specification
规范的特定版本
the collection of artifacts is something
文物的收集是东西
that is distributed as a unit and it's
作为一个单位分布，它是
thought to be indivisible for again for
被认为是不可分割的
any particular version there's no rule
任何特定版本都没有规则
that suggests that the TCK be
这表明TCK是
represented in any particular project so
在任何特定项目中都有代表
what we're seeing right now for example
例如，我们现在所看到的
is we have a single TCK project that
是我们有一个TCK项目吗
covers most of our specifications in the
涵盖了我们大部分的规格
Jakarta space and that's fine it's
雅加达空间，这很好
actually part of a I guess that part of
其实是我的一部分
a different project thought I'd talk
我想谈一个不同的项目
just briefly about the the process
简要介绍一下过程
overview the the day-to-day work of of
概述的日常工作
the committers and I've highlighted the
提交者，我强调了
creation review part here because for
创作评论部分在这里，因为
specification projects were actually
规范项目实际上是
kind of at that stage right now strictly
现在严格来说是在那个阶段
speaking we have a bunch of regular old
说我们有一堆普通的老
Eclipse open source projects right now
Eclipse开源项目现在
that contains some specification content
包含一些规范内容
and part of our process to to engage in
也是我们参与的过程的一部分
the specification development work will
规范制定工作将
be to convert these into specification
将这些转换成规格
process projects I did a quick look and
处理项目，我做了快速浏览，
it's looking like a
看起来像
of the specification projects these are
在规范项目中，这些是
all the ones called the Eclipse project
所有这些都称为Eclipse项目
for something have a lot of the project
因为有很多项目
teams have reworked their scopes which
团队重新调整了范围
is pretty cool so we've got you've got
很酷，所以我们有您拥有
some fairly well defined scopes on these
关于这些的一些相当明确的范围
projects so we're gonna you know at some
项目，所以我们会知道一些
point we need to move these projects
点，我们需要移动这些项目
forward and turn them into specification
转发并将其变成规范
projects so that we can can you know do
项目，以便我们可以知道
the actual specification work part of
实际的规范工作部分
that is getting the scope right part of
那就是将示波器的正确部分
that is we're going to require that the
那就是我们将要求
committers committers or need to provide
提交者或需要提供
us with a little bit of new paperwork
给我们一些新的文书工作
some more paperwork and and and then
一些文书工作，然后
again we'll move forward into a
再次，我们将前进到
development phase the reviews through
开发阶段通过审查
this process all require approval from
此过程都需要得到以下方面的批准
the specification committee of a a
机管局规格委员会
working group that this is a committee
工作组，这是一个委员会
that's basically put together to provide
基本上放在一起提供
some governance and oversight of the
一些治理和监督
specification process specifically for
专门针对的规范过程
the Jakarta projects and so once again
雅加达项目，因此再次
as part of that we get we get their
作为一部分，我们得到了我们得到的
approval on the creation review and the
批准创作审查和
progress review much like with the the
进度审查与
JCP Executive Committee the way that the
JCP执行委员会认为
specification committee votes the
规格委员会对
criteria that they follow is what we're
他们遵循的标准就是我们
looking for is that they're they're
寻找的是他们是
ensuring that projects are staying
确保项目停滞不前
within scope and that they're they're
在范围内，他们是他们
operating sort of with it with good good
很好的操作
intentions and in the specification
意图和规范
process and with with each review that
流程以及每次审核时
the specification committee just gets an
规格委员会刚得到一个
opportunity to ensure that this is true
有机会确保这是真的
so the specification committee gets a
因此规格委员会得到了
chance to to weigh in on the plan for
有机会权衡计划
new development they get they get an
他们得到的新发展他们得到了
opportunity to to approve the progress
批准进度的机会
of a project and then ultimately when a
一个项目，然后最终
project engages in a standard release
项目参与标准发布
review for the Eclipse development
Eclipse开发的评论
process the specification committee gets
处理规格委员会得到的
a vote as well the specification itself
投票以及规范本身
goes through a transformation after a
经过一个
release review
发布审查
become ratified kind of kind of a make
成为一种认可的品牌
marking the specification official and
将规范标记为正式
it's at that point when a specification
就在那时
is ratified that implementers can can
被批准实施者可以
claim compatibility with a specification
声称与规范兼容
anyway
无论如何
this really all I intended to to speak
这真的是我想说的
about today just a little brief overview
关于今天只是一个简短的概述
remind people were what we're doing and
提醒人们我们在做什么，
where we are in the process and with
我们在哪里以及与
that i'll i'm happy to answer any
我会很乐意回答任何
questions you can also send me questions
您也可以向我发送问题
directly to my email weigh in at
直接到我的电子邮件中
eclipse.org okay thanks Wayne Thanks
eclipse.org好的，谢谢，韦恩，谢谢
thanks to Talia so we'll open this for
感谢Talia，所以我们将为此打开
there's normal questions I do see some
我确实有一些正常的问题
questions in the chat as well and I also
聊天中的问题，我也
see you have answered quite a few so if
看到你已经回答了很多，所以如果
there is something else you know do let
你知道还有别的东西让
us know and we will you know have these
我们知道，我们会知道你有这些
sessions one excuse me once a month and
会议每个月打扰一次，
we'll give you a plenty of opportunity
我们会给您很多机会
to to ask us questions I also want to
向我们提问我也想
mention that next week we have a Jakarta
提到下周我们有一个雅加达
town hall and I hope you all got the
市政厅，我希望你们都得到了
notification about that so feel free to
关于此的通知，请随时
join that session also and the then you
也加入该会话，然后您
will have the opportunity to kind of ask
有机会询问
questions from members of various
来自各成员的问题
members of the working group on the
工作组成员
status of Jakarta and where we're going
雅加达的状态以及我们要去的地方
what has been done and so on so with
已经做了什么，依此类推
that are we are there any questions that
那是我们有什么疑问吗
still need answering
还需要回答
so can you tweet the link to the Jakarta
所以你能发推文到雅加达的链接吗
eat uncle absolutely
绝对吃un
I don't think there is going to be a
我认为不会有
live stream but there is a session and a
直播，但有一个会话和一个
link that we are providing to zoom where
我们提供的链接可以放大到
you would be able to join so it is we
您将能够加入，所以我们
also have the meetup organized and the
也有组织聚会和
meetup is going to point you to the zoo
聚会会带你去动物园
link so hang in there for that when do
链接，以便在那里做
you see or italia any additional
你看到或意大利任何其他
questions that you would like to answer
您想回答的问题
I see your question on the the licenses
我在许可证上看到了您的问题
I think I Wayne mentioned all the
我想韦恩提到了所有
licenses that are related your general
与您的一般相关的许可证
project available somewhere Italia I
意大利某地可用的项目
think that question is for you yeah that
认为这个问题适合您，是的，
shirt as we bidding okay I put there at
衬衫，我们竞标好了，我放在那儿
the answer okay sounds great
答案很好听起来不错
so where I can find the code at github
所以我可以在github上找到代码
so you if you go to Jakarta EE Jakarta
所以你如果你去雅加达EE雅加达
sorry dot e link you will find the
抱歉，您会找到e链接
pointers from there if you don't find it
如果找不到它，从那里指向指针
please you know contact us in a
请您知道与我们联系
different way and we'll send you the
不同的方式，我们将向您发送
direct link yeah you can also please
直接链接是的，你也可以
don't forget from the Jakarta Tech Talks
不要忘记雅加达技术讲座
where you join this session to subscribe
您在此会话中进行订阅的位置
to all the look at the pointers to get
看看所有的指针
social right and subscribe to the
社会权利并订阅
YouTube channel to Twitter or Facebook
YouTube频道到Twitter或Facebook
Linkedin and to help us so to promote
Linkedin并帮助我们促进
Jakarta e
雅加达
we also absolutely love to see more
我们也非常乐意看到更多
members of the top tech talk meetup
顶级技术讲座聚会的成员
check out the tech talk meet up so
查看技术交流会，以便
please join the meetup and yeah I'll
请参加聚会，我会的
pass out so with all of this
昏昏欲睡
thank you very very much for joining our
非常感谢您加入我们
first session and you're more than
第一次会议，您不仅
welcome to join us for the tactile
欢迎加入我们的触觉
connects to become with you and then of
连接在一起成为你，然后
course in February we're looking forward
当然，我们期待着
to see you again thank you so very much
再次见到你，非常感谢你
and I will stop the broadcast right now
我现在要停止广播
and we'll talk later bye
我们待会再谈